<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Joe Garrett</title>
    <link>https://jlgarrett.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Joe Garrett</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 12:13:11 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jlgarrett.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://jlgarrett.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jlgarrett.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>In my time, I have worked on a few different projects, mostly related to imaging and measurement.
Current projects:
HYPSO the hyperspectral imaging cubesat
ADRASSO looking for rust
Older projects:
Will be updated!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publication of On-board Clustering Analysis</title>
      <link>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/som-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 12:13:11 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/som-clustering/</guid>
      <description>A paper authored by one of the masters students whom I co-advised (and co-authored by myself) has recently been published.
We investigated the possibility of using a shallow neural network, called a self-organizing map, as a way of clustering hyperspectral data on-board the HYPSO cubesat.
Clustering is a very flexible operation in machine learning which can pre-process data so that it can be analyzed by other algorithms more easily. For example, because clustering groups similar pixels together, a classification algorithm can operate more quickly by analysing the clusters (a few hundred) rather than the individual pixels (a few hundred thousand), which provides a significant speed improvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation at AMOS day</title>
      <link>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/amos-day-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 15:03:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/amos-day-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I gave a presentation at the once-a-semester AMOS Day event, where researchers from AMOS at NTNU get together to discuss their projects.
The focus of my talk was the hyperspectral camera that the NTNU small satellite team has been working on. I focused on two of our interesting findings that I and a collegue presented at conferences earlier this year.
First, I spoke about a fast resampling procedure that we developed to correct for smile and keystone in spectrograms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity and accuracy analysis published</title>
      <link>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/my-second-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 15:03:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/my-second-post/</guid>
      <description>A paper that I had written with a few colleagues from the University of Maryland was just published.
The article discusses the sensitivity and accuracy that we achieved (at UMD) in measurements of the Casimir force in air and discusses they might be improved.
I wrote this paper with future graduate students as the target audience. In one sense, it is everything that I wish I knew about how to measure the Casimir force before starting a PhD studying it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this website for?</title>
      <link>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/why-a-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 15:03:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jlgarrett.github.io/posts/why-a-website/</guid>
      <description>I am making this website to:
 share informal information about projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on link the projects to repositories share occassional thoughts on technological development  This site will primarily be a location show a little about the projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on over the past decade or so. The associated scientific papers are not the best introductions. They&amp;rsquo;re a little too technical.
An informal explanation of the methodology and results should help other scientists decide whether or not they want to adopt a technique.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
